VARUN SWARUP

Computer Science Engineer

in linkedin.com/in/varunswarup0/

github.com/varunswarup0/

PROFILE

Seasoned and independent Front End Developer with six months of experience in blending the art of design with the skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, proactive feature optimization, and relentless debugging

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Intern

PepCoding Education

March 2021 - present

- Developed Cricket Scrapper, an automated data scraping mechanism devised to extract and store data of cricket players from the ESPNcricinfo website
- Showed a vast amount of responsibility to learn and zeal to take on new assignments challenges

Full Stack Development Intern Codeacious Technologies

May 2020 - November 2020

- Worked on the project Regiman, an ECIA design registration management that bridges the gap between manufacturers, distributors, and sales representatives
- Excelled in designing user experience and user interfaces

PROJECTS

Think Piece 🖸 🞧

React | Firebase

- A live blogging platform for all of your hottest takes
- Includes features such as querying & updating, OAuth, security rules, authentication & user documents, and cloud functions

Adopt Me 🞧

React Hooks React Context API

- A react powered website that communicates with an API client for retrieving information about pets that can be adopted
- Made using hooks, class components, error boundaries, and router

Tweet Stream

Redux Redux-Thunk

 A real-time Tweet streaming app to listen for and display Tweets based on JavaScript in order to understand what's happening in the public conversation

SKILLS

C | CPP Java HTML **XHTML** SASS **Bootstrap JavaScript** React Firebase **jQuery** Git GitHub WordPress Redux **Data Structures** SQL Algorithm Design & Analysis

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, New Delhi

2018 - present

★ CGPA 9.022 (Till 5th Sem)

Class 12, Pragati Public School CBSE Board

2018

★ Percentage 84.8

Class 10, Pragati Public School CBSE Board

2016

★ CGPA 10

COURSES

C++ Launchpad 🖸

Coding Blocks

January 2019 - April 2019

A uniquely designed course in Data Structures and Algorithms

Competitive Programming Coding Blocks

June 2019 - August 2019

An ultimate online competitive coding training

STRENGTHS

- Oral and Written Communication
- Committed to Lifelong Learning
- ✓ Reliable and Consistent